In the next few videos, we'll talk about large scale machine learning.
在接下来的几个视频，我们将谈论大规模机器学习。（字幕翻译：中国海洋大学 黄海广 haiguang2000@qq.com）
That is, algorithms but viewing with big data sets.
也就是大数据集的算法。
If you look back at a recent 5 or 10-year history of machine learning.
如果你看看最近5年或10年机器学习的历史。
One of the reasons that learning algorithms work so much better now than even say, 5-years ago,
一个原因就是：现在的一个学习算法比5年前更好，
is just the sheer amount of data that we have now and that we can train our algorithms on.
只是说我们现在，我们在数据量极其庞大可以训练我们的算法。
In these next few videos, we'll talk about algorithms for dealing when we have such massive data sets.
在接下来的视频，我们将谈论时，当我们有如此庞大的数据集的算法处理。
So why do we want to use such large data sets?
我们为什么要用这么大的数据集？
We've already seen that one of the best ways to get a high performance machine learning system,
我们已经看到了一个得到一个高性能的机器学习系统的最佳途径，
is if you take a low-bias learning algorithm, and train that on a lot of data.
如果你采取低偏差的学习算法，并对大量数据进行训练。
And so, one early example we have already seen was this example of classifying between confusable words.
一个早期的例子，我们已经看到了一个分类容易混淆的词的例子。
So, for breakfast, I ate two (TWO) eggs and we saw in this example, these sorts of results,
上面的例子分类的结果，早餐我吃了（TWO）个鸡蛋
where, you know, so long as you feed the algorithm a lot of data, it seems to do very well.
如你所知，只要你给的算法很多数据，它似乎做的很好。
And so it's results like these that has led to the saying in machine learning that
所以这样的结果表明，在机器学习中，
often it's not who has the best algorithm that wins. It's who has the most data.
决定因素往往不是那些拥有最好的算法，而是这是谁的数据多。
So you want to learn from large data sets, at least when we can get such large data sets.
所以你想从大型数据集的学习，至少我们得获得这样的大型数据集。
But learning with large data sets comes with its own unique problems, specifically, computational problems.
但大型数据集的学习都有自己独特的问题，特别是计算问题。
Let's say your training set size is M equals 100,000,000.
我们说你的训练集的大小为M = 100000000。
And this is actually pretty realistic for many modern data sets.
其实这是很现实的许多现代数据集。
If you look at the US Census data set, if there are, you know,
如果你看看美国人口普查数据，如果有的话，你知道的，
300 million people in the US, you can usually get hundreds of millions of records.
在美国有三亿人口，你通常可以得到成千上万的记录。
If you look at the amount of traffic that popular websites get,
如果你看流行的网站的流量数据，
you easily get training sets that are much larger than hundreds of millions of examples.
你轻易得到的训练集，一亿数据还大得多。
And let's say you want to train a linear regression model, or maybe a logistic regression model,
让我们说你想训练一个线性回归模型，或者一个Logistic回归模型，
in which case this is the gradient descent rule.
在这种情况下，这是梯度下降规则。
And if you look at what you need to do to compute the gradient,
如果你看看你需要做什么来计算梯度，
which is this term over here, then when M is a hundred million,
这个词在这里是，当m是一亿，
you need to carry out a summation over a hundred million terms,
你需要进行求和一亿条，
in order to compute these derivatives terms and to perform a single step of decent.
为了计算这些导数和单步下降。
Because of the computational expense of summing over a hundred million entries
因为总的超过一亿次的计算
in order to compute just one step of gradient descent,
为了计算只是一步梯度下降，
in the next few videos we've spoken about techniques
在接下来的几个视频我们已经谈论
for either replacing this with something else or to find more efficient ways to compute this derivative.
或者更换这东西或找到更有效的方法来计算这个导数。
By the end of this sequence of videos on large scale machine learning,
通过观看大规模机器学习的视频，
you know how to fit models, linear regression, logistic regression, neural networks and so on
你知道如何适应模型，线性回归，logistic回归，神经网络等
even today's data sets with, say, a hundred million examples.
甚至说，今天的数据集达到一亿例。
Of course, before we put in the effort into training a model with a hundred million examples,
当然，在我们尝试把一亿个样本放入训练模型，
We should also ask ourselves, well, why not use just a thousand examples.
我们也应该问问自己，为什么不使用一千个样本？
Maybe we can randomly pick the subsets of a thousand examples
也许我们可以随机选择一千个样本的子集，
out of a hundred million examples and train our algorithm on just a thousand examples.
通过一亿个样本得到的训练算法用于一千个样本。
So before investing the effort into actually developing and the software needed to train these massive models
所以投资前，努力发展和实际需要训练这些大规模模型的软件
is often a good sanity check, if training on just a thousand examples might do just as well.
往往是一个很好的检查，如果在一千个例子训练可能会做的一样。
The way to sanity check of using a much smaller training set might do just as well,
的使用一个非常小的训练集的完整性检查的方式可能会做的一样，
that is if using a much smaller n equals 1000 size training set,
如果使用一个非常小的训练集，n等于1000，
that might do just as well, it is the usual method of plotting the learning curves,
会做的一样好，它是通常学习曲线的绘制方法，
so if you were to plot the learning curves and if your training objective were to look like this,
如果你要画的学习曲线，如果你的训练目的是看起来像这样，
that's J train theta.
这是Jtrain（θ），
And if your cross-validation set objective, Jcv of theta would look like this,
如果你的交叉验证，设定目标，JCV（θ）看起来像这样
then this looks like a high-variance learning algorithm,
这看起来像一个高方差学习算法，
and we will be more confident that adding extra training examples would improve performance.
我们会更有信心，增加额外的培训例子会提高性能。
Whereas in contrast if you were to plot the learning curves,
而相反如果你策划的学习曲线，
if your training objective were to look like this, and if your cross-validation objective were to look like that,
如果你训练的目的是这个样子的，如果你的交叉验证的目的是那个样子，
then this looks like the classical high-bias learning algorithm.
然后像经典的高偏差学习算法。
And in the latter case, you know, if you were to plot this up to,
在后一种情况下，你知道，如果你这样画，
say, m equals 1000 and so that is m equals 500 up to m equals 1000,
M等于1000，所以这是m等于500到m等于1000，
then it seems unlikely that increasing m to a hundred million will do much better
看起来不太可能增加m到一亿会做得更好
and then you'd be just fine sticking to n equals 1000,
然后你得坚持n等于1000，
rather than investing a lot of effort to figure out how the scale of the algorithm.
而不是投入了很多努力弄清如何算法的尺度。
Of course, if you were in the situation shown by the figure on the right,
当然，如果你在右图这种情况，
then one natural thing to do would be to add extra features,
自然而然将会添加额外的特征，
or add extra hidden units to your neural network and so on,
或在你的神经网络添加额外的隐藏单元，等等，
so that you end up with a situation closer to that on the left, where maybe this is up to n equals 1000,
你最终接近左侧的情况，而这也许是到n等于1000，
and this then gives you more confidence that trying to add infrastructure to change the algorithm
并给你更多的信心，努力把基础设施改变算法
to use much more than a thousand examples that might actually be a good use of your time.
使用超过一千的样本，实际上可能是很好的利用你的时间。
So in large-scale machine learning, we like to come up with computationally reasonable ways,
如此大规模的机器学习，我们要拿出合理的计算方法，
or computationally efficient ways, to deal with very big data sets.
或计算的有效方法，处理非常大的数据集。
In the next few videos, we'll see two main ideas.
在接下来的几个视频，我们会看到两个主要观点。
The first is called stochastic gradient descent and the second is called Map Reduce, for viewing with very big data sets.
第一种称为随机梯度下降，第二是图的减少，观察的非常大的数据集。
And after you've learned about these methods, hopefully that will allow you to scale up your learning algorithms to big data
当你了解了这些方法，希望这将允许你扩大你的学习算法在大数据
and allow you to get much better performance on many different applications.
让你在许多不同的应用得到更好的性能。